<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>From Tumblr on Yet Another Geographer</title>
    <link>/tags/from-tumblr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in From Tumblr on Yet Another Geographer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 08:46:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/from-tumblr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I often find myself looking for spaces like those I used to like in Brooklyn or Phoenix</title>
      <link>/i-often-find-myself-looking-for-spaces-like-those/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 08:46:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/i-often-find-myself-looking-for-spaces-like-those/</guid>
      <description>rather than taking what I like about places I find in Bristol at face value.
I guess sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s hard to relinquish that inherent comparative streak.
Regardless, I&amp;rsquo;m still seeking that best pub that does good coffee and serves beer by 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>this should probably be a tweet</title>
      <link>/this-should-probably-be-a-tweet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 17:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/this-should-probably-be-a-tweet/</guid>
      <description>Modern &amp;ldquo;nerd&amp;rdquo; media (rick &amp;amp; morty, bojack, &amp;ldquo;deep&amp;rdquo; analyses of pop media like the insufferable &amp;ldquo;man drones over film clip&amp;rdquo; channels on youtube or &amp;ldquo;Scar No One Else Can See&amp;rdquo; by &amp;ldquo;Fairy Lives Matter&amp;rdquo; movie writer Max Landis) &amp;amp; the politically-opposed alt-right adjacent podcast sphere (J. Peterson, Sam Harris, etc) have really demonstrated that the first stanza of Hot Fries is way too real:
talking fast with a dense amount of facile textual references really makes people think you&amp;rsquo;re deep.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am sure my dissertation would be finished</title>
      <link>/i-am-sure-my-dissertation-would-be-finished/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2017 15:45:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/i-am-sure-my-dissertation-would-be-finished/</guid>
      <description>if I could locate half the files &amp;amp; notebooks I&amp;rsquo;ve started in my dropbox</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The joys of using political data</title>
      <link>/the-joys-of-using-political-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 18:08:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/the-joys-of-using-political-data/</guid>
      <description>When you work with Census-derived data, you can usually be sure it meets some standard of regularity, which makes it easy to use with other data. Where it doesn’t, people have built When you work with congressional district data, you’re in for a bad time. Right now, I’m working on relating the CLEA to the cdmaps maintained by UCLA.
This poses a few challenges. First, CLEA records are one big, flat table of candidates who’ve run in a contest within some legislative constituency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress in (a) Human Geography</title>
      <link>/progress-in-a-human-geography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:18:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/progress-in-a-human-geography/</guid>
      <description>I spent a lot of my undergraduate trying to whittle down haughtier edges of my supposedly sharp mind.
I am spending a lot of my graduate school experience being told those edges should be sharper. That my writing or my thinking has too many “could,” “may,” and “likely.” That I sell myself, my product, or my ideas short via qualifications and pervasive focus on the challenges my work faces or might face rather than the successes I may have at hand and or have had before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lit Review Habits</title>
      <link>/lit-review-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 21:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/lit-review-habits/</guid>
      <description>thejennawynn:
 Let’s go, academics. Share your tips on how you keep all your sources and notes straight while doing a literature review.
Zotero’s a great bibliography program that can use a simple button on your browser to import the info and pdfs from places like JSTOR or even just webpages. I use the “extra” line to note whether I’ve read/notated/printed/etc. that particular work as well as using the ‘notes’ feature to put specific info i think might be quotable for my own work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And what did we learn today, kids?</title>
      <link>/and-what-did-we-learn-today-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 18:34:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/and-what-did-we-learn-today-kids/</guid>
      <description>When you estimate a logit over ratios with significantly independent numerator and denominator with significant heterogeneity, your model can get really mangled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s funny how a little math can simplify a function call</title>
      <link>/its-funny-how-a-little-math-can-simplify-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 15:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/its-funny-how-a-little-math-can-simplify-a/</guid>
      <description>from 30 lines to 5 lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>/knowing-when-to-stop-reading-and-start-writing-is/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 23:39:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/knowing-when-to-stop-reading-and-start-writing-is/</guid>
      <description>Knowing when to stop reading and start writing is hard. Especially when you&amp;rsquo;re very interested in what you&amp;rsquo;re reading.
I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful for this literature review Wednesday, but I make no promises&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>