<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clustering on Yet Another Geographer</title>
    <link>/tags/clustering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clustering on Yet Another Geographer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 02:20:45 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/clustering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GISRUK II: Spatially-Encouraged Spectral Clustering</title>
      <link>/post/2018-gisruk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 02:20:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-gisruk/</guid>
      <description>This paper culminates a bit of work I&amp;rsquo;ve started on since seeing a talk by Phil Chodrow on a paper that eventually became his quite interesting NAS paper paper on segregation and entropy surfaces.
I was intrigued by the prospect of using spectral clustering for constrained clustering problems. Specifically, I&amp;rsquo;d known that affinity matrix clustering could be adapted to constrained contexts ever since reading about hierarchical ward clustering, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen a really convincing method that showed me how I could work this out for a general affinity-matrix clustering method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>price clusters in airbnbs in brooklyn</title>
      <link>/its-neat-that-this-new-algorithm-is-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 20:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/its-neat-that-this-new-algorithm-is-working/</guid>
      <description>I find that the hardest part for me to be motivated about is the stage right after I finish the proof of concept. It&amp;rsquo;s like&amp;hellip; once the new stuff is done, I get much less interested than when I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to figure it out.
I guess that&amp;rsquo;s probably pretty common among researchers, but the thrill of wrestling with a genuinely new problem is interesting, enjoyable, and difficult. Sometimes, it feels like documenting that wrestling is a bit tedious.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>