<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Yet Another Geographer</title>
    <link>/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Yet Another Geographer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 20:48:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzles about (mis)Replication</title>
      <link>/puzzles-about-misreplication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 20:48:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/puzzles-about-misreplication/</guid>
      <description>So, a while back, I was using a new compactness metric to extend some gerrymandering studies. In attempting the replication, I found some minor math errors in the original paper that made it diffcult to get valid values for the statistic.
After trying multiple times to verify whether it was my code or if the published statistic had some typographical error, I went to the original author, shared my concerns, and found that it did.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Untitled</title>
      <link>/kinda-nice-when-the-model-youre-working-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 04:10:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/kinda-nice-when-the-model-youre-working-with/</guid>
      <description> Photo Caption: Kinda nice when the model you’re working with clearly is trying to work.  imported from: yetanothergeographer </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trajectories &amp; Transitions</title>
      <link>/trajectories-transitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 18:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/trajectories-transitions/</guid>
      <description>I started my PhD running away from Political Science/Political Geography as fast as I could, into Industrial Engineering and Computer Science-y topics. I’m still what many would call a “methodologist,” am wholly entertained by computational geometry &amp;amp; statistics, and enjoy math and programming a little too much to be fully motivated by applied work. But, gradually, I’ve started filtering back, situated with some top-flight quantitative geographers at the GeoDa Center for Spatial Analysis and Geocomputation, into work by Micah Altman, Andrew Gelman, Gary King, Jowei Chen, and Jonathan Rodden&amp;hellip; tons of political scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>