<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Yet Another Geographer</title>
    <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Yet Another Geographer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 13:19:44 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ljwolf.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on a sabbatical and a spring return</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/seattle-and-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 13:19:44 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/seattle-and-later/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my sincere hope to make sure this blog extends beyond my &lt;em&gt;grad school to first permanent job&lt;/em&gt; period, I will be setting aside some very explicit time to write upates here again. Some of my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ljwolf.org/posts/challenge/&#34;&gt;favorite&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ljwolf.org/posts/olsson-counterfactuals/&#34;&gt;bits&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ljwolf.org/posts/geometry/&#34;&gt;writing&lt;/a&gt; live here. I recall getting told once during graduate school that my exam answers &amp;ldquo;read like a blog post&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; I think that was meant to get me to straighten up and write like a spatial scientist, but I actually (unsurprisingly) like the more confessional &lt;em&gt;verbal&lt;/em&gt; vernacular way of talking about research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A stray thought on the US, UK, and celebrity in Politics</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/celebs-in-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2022 13:29:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/celebs-in-politics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of people criticize American democracy for being very celebrity-driven,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in the sense that the media portrays it often as a set of individual conflicts between celebrity-politicians whose career trajectory is ultimately decided by name recognition. But, because there&amp;rsquo;s no one point of media focus, opposition politicians can avoid position-taking&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; fairly easily… they can keep their head down. Conversely, this means that opposition politicians that want to “break out” of their current party hierarchy can use the media as a tool to circumvent the party.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Famously Bad Gamble</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/stpetersburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 09:46:42 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/stpetersburg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Man, I am &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; easily &lt;a href=&#34;https://xkcd.com/356/&#34;&gt;nerd-sniped&lt;/a&gt;. First, I can just tell that &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/Vv6nePZ7t6?amp=1&#34;&gt;the wedding profession matcher&lt;/a&gt; is going to push me to dig out all sorts of weird, distinctive patterns in the pairings between professionals. But, recently, I found myself idly simulating the answer to another kind of question altogether.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-st-petersburg-paradox&#34;&gt;The St. Petersburg Paradox&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Petersburg_paradox&#34;&gt;The St. Petersburg Paradox&lt;/a&gt; describes a game with a mathematically &amp;ldquo;infinite&amp;rdquo; expected payoff but one that definitely &lt;em&gt;does not&lt;/em&gt; feel worth playing. The &lt;a href=&#34;(https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/St._Petersburg_paradox)&#34;&gt;Wikipedia article&lt;/a&gt; is quite good on the subject, but to put it briefly here:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Dispatch is Awesome</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/dynamicdispatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 13:58:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/dynamicdispatch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;tldr: the social and technical architecture of object-oriented programming encourages us to centralize our focus onto a few core implementations, objects, of the main concepts we use. This creates coordination problems when we want to extend or modify them; we have to work together and agree on how an object in the commons is modified. Alternatively, dynamic dispatch, a programming strategy that makes the proceedures we exececute depend on the types of their input, solves these social and technical challenges with very few tradeoffsin general. I recommend using it, if you have not, through the &lt;code&gt;functools.singledispatch&lt;/code&gt; library in Python, or the &lt;code&gt;multipledispatch&lt;/code&gt; library.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is depopulation harder to redistrict?</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/depop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 17:07:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/depop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last month and a half or so, my colleagues at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bristol.ac.uk/geography/research/quantitative-spatial-science/&#34;&gt;University of Bristol Quantitative Spatial Sciences Lab (QuSS)&lt;/a&gt; have done a hell of a job examining the &lt;a href=&#34;https://boundarycommissionforengland.independent.gov.uk/2023-review/&#34;&gt;Boundary Commission for England&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s draft plan for Westminster Parliamentary Constituencies across England. We published our findings in &lt;a href=&#34;https://ljwolf.org/projects/bce/report.pdf&#34;&gt;a report&lt;/a&gt; and a webmap (&lt;a href=&#34;https://ljwolf.org/bce&#34;&gt;with explanation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ljwolf.org/bcemap&#34;&gt;full-screen&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing that was &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; surprising to me is the interplay between depopulation and boundary change:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;(c), surprise! the North is pretty re-drawn. It could be due to population change (which is generally pretty rough on the shape of constituencies) but the rapidly-growing South West is the least-redrawn part of the map! Is depopulation harder to redistrict? Needs more science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Something just hit me about a month after I turned thirty</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/thirty/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 14:59:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/thirty/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For all the change, contrast, and development that arises from your first thirty years, in the second (or third, I suppose, if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky&amp;hellip;) do you just basically continue to exist how you are?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, you&amp;rsquo;re not going back to college, learning to play the piano again, choosing another career&amp;hellip; nobody in my generation has (or will have) the time or means for that, if we&amp;rsquo;re lucky enough for it to be an option.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The disappointing finitude of screens</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/on-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 15:57:51 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/on-media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve started to realize over lockdown, as I have restricted access to books, printers&amp;hellip; physical media, is that the new paradigm of touch heavy full screen apps is fundamentally opposed to the “physical” mode of interaction that the desktop computing metaphor tried to mimic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Concerns about skeumorphism aside, the main idea of physical desktops that the desktop computing metaphor matches is that you can arrange documents/windows into stacks within a work area. Reading a book and writing notes? Put the book to one side and your notes on the other (if you&amp;rsquo;ve got the dead tree version) or put the pdf on one side and your Notion on the other (if you&amp;rsquo;re pushing pixels). This seems pretty fundamental for the &amp;ldquo;window&amp;rdquo;-based desktop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boomeranging: It&#39;s all coming back to us</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/boomerang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 10:59:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/boomerang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting very interested in the concept of the &amp;ldquo;boomerang generation&amp;rdquo; and the tension that broader social trend has with ideas around &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/10/style/cottagecore.html&#34;&gt;Cottagecore&lt;/a&gt;. They&amp;rsquo;re two very strong forces acting on the middle class&amp;hellip; returning to intergenerational houses, folks can afford to live in the city. But, if the young increasingly &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; want to live in cities due to changing tastes and preferences, then we get another wave of suburbanization. Given my own short stint &amp;ldquo;boomeranging&amp;rdquo; to the countryside during the COVID-19 lockdown,&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been very intrigued by the intersection of the &amp;ldquo;return of the multi-generational&amp;rdquo; household and (possible) change in the tastes and preferences of young, house-buying people.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gunnar Olsson and the Counterfactual Imagination in Geography</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/olsson-counterfactuals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 22:21:38 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/olsson-counterfactuals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I suppose I&amp;rsquo;m writing this as an act of defiance against the lethargy of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.independent.co.uk/life-style/health-and-families/coronavirus-lockdown-tired-sleepy-fatigue-daylight-routine-a9450196.html&#34;&gt;Great Stall&lt;/a&gt;, or maybe just a way to &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/2399808320943989&#34;&gt;process some feelings&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ve really tried to branch out across the full set of geography recently. I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading so much more than I used to, especially across the breadth of human geography. It&amp;rsquo;s been enlightening.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For instance, after finishing the &lt;em&gt;excellent&lt;/em&gt; piece on the discontinuing of the Univeristy of Michigan department of geography by &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1080/24694452.2020.1760780&#34;&gt;Huntley and Rosenblum&lt;/a&gt;, I found myself working back through some of Olsson&amp;rsquo;s work. Mentioned in the same breath as Tobler in &lt;em&gt;The Omega Affair&lt;/em&gt; piece by Huntley and Rosenblum, I was surprised: the Olsson I was familiar with published a few strikingly novel (but ultimately dead-ended) pieces of quantitative geography in the 1970s, focusing on the possibility of detecting regularities in distance decay functions and interaction models. Basically, the &lt;em&gt;du jour&lt;/em&gt; topic of regional science at the time, in the throes of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://search.proquest.com/openview/085238550a227ac07ed0e44dc0d1932e/1?pq-origsite=gscholar&amp;amp;cbl=18750&amp;amp;diss=y&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Structure Debate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; my friend Taylor writes so eloquently about, Olsson just registered as a &amp;ldquo;big name&amp;rdquo; to me, in the realm of Berry &amp;amp; possibly even Wilson, but not someone as field-defining to me as Tobler, Golledge, or Johnston.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Modelling 2 Lectures: Topics in Advanced Spatial Modelling</title>
      <link>https://ljwolf.org/posts/2020-sm2-lectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 12:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ljwolf.org/posts/2020-sm2-lectures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For an intro &amp;amp; discussion of some of the fundamental ideas in spatial statistics, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover a few main topics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;logistics&#34;&gt;Logistics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Courses start at 11AM on the date listed. The &amp;ldquo;Join Remotely&amp;rdquo; links will work at 10AM for students to check their AV equipment. The remote sessions will be open from 11AM, through both practical sessions (1-3PM, 4-6PM).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;plotting--spatial-relationships-in-r&#34;&gt;Plotting &amp;amp; spatial relationships in R&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;a href=&#34;https://ljwolf.org/teaching/2020-sm2-00.html&#34;&gt;notebook&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This practical/component will cover some of the fundamental concepts in quantitative geography, such as:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
