<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spatial Analysis on Yet Another Geographer</title>
    <link>/tags/spatial-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spatial Analysis on Yet Another Geographer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 19:12:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/spatial-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RFC for GSOC Feedback</title>
      <link>/rfc-for-gsoc-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 19:12:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/rfc-for-gsoc-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Clarifying a Core Data Model for PySAL  Gist here From my perspective, I see my proposal for GSOC as containing two oblique foci. My hope in drafting this notebook for my fellow authors is to make this clear.
I think at this point, many people who use &amp;amp; develop PySAL would like to see better tooling for Pandas$\leftrightarrow$PySAL interaction. This was started by Luc, Dani, &amp;amp; myself in the pysal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on a hard-won win for PySAL</title>
      <link>/reflections-on-a-hard-won-win-for-pysal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2015 21:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reflections-on-a-hard-won-win-for-pysal/</guid>
      <description>As a way to learn Python (and I mean really come to know it), I took on the project of converting PySAL to be compatible with Python 3.
I started work on this two years ago. A tentative candidate for release is available in my fork
Now, I’m glad I did this. I still worry about the day when Apple decides to ship the next OSX (Half Moon Bay? Big Sur?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some New Realizations on Oooooold Material</title>
      <link>/some-new-realizations-on-oooooold-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2014 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/some-new-realizations-on-oooooold-material/</guid>
      <description>For my TA appointment for the Masters in Applied Sciences program, I am having to generate some lectures on statistical theory. Because of some interest across the program in improving the statistics portion of the curriculum, I wrote about two weeks of lectures and assignments on spatial statistics, pushing from a start point of the Kolmogorov Axioms, fundamental results in elementary probability theory all the way up through spatial regression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>starting to learn julia</title>
      <link>/i-guess-this-is-how-productivity-works-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 05:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/i-guess-this-is-how-productivity-works-terminal/</guid>
      <description>That aside, I&amp;rsquo;ve forked the Shapefile.jl repo and put in some goals to further Julia&amp;rsquo;s spatial analysis capabilities. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what the community ethics/practices are for Julia, but I&amp;rsquo;m always slightly nervous about being the first fork on a repo that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been touched in a few months. I can&amp;rsquo;t really explain why. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just a concern that my preference for private repos and anonymous contribution makes my github page look sparse.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>